Kyle Rassweiler

Chone: +1-613-724-9141 | ■ Email: jobs@kylerassweiler.ca

♠ Portfolio: https://portfolio.kylerassweiler.ca | ♠ Github: www.github.com/rassweiler

Summary

Engineering Specialist with experience in: software development, networking, programmable logic controllers, robotics, electronics, and machining.

Skills

Software Angular, Apache2, Assembly(PIC), C++, CMake, Django, Git, HTML,

JavaScript, Meteor, Mongoose, Node, PHP, Python, React, Redux

Virtualisation Qemu/KVM, Docker, XCP-NG

Systems FreeBSD, Arch, Debian, Windows, Proxmox

Projects

KRelloA simple Trello clone developed using react and redux with jest

and enzyme for testing. Used Javascript, SCSS, and HTML to style

the react components.

Site: https://portfolio.kylerassweiler.ca/software/krello/

Demo: https://krello.kylerassweiler.com/
Source: https://github.com/rassweiler/krello

KR-Display A responsive Meteor application for the display of SQL data. The

system uses jobs to schedule information updates from the SQL server, the jobs then update the local MongoDB database. This dashboard displays production information, allowing management to

track and minimise downtime.

Site: https://portfolio.kylerassweiler.ca/software/kr-display/

Source: https://github.com/rassweiler/kr-display

Kawasaki AS Parser A Kawasaki robot backup parser written in TypeScript for browser

or Node. The library also includes TypeScript interfaces for use

in new projects.

Website: https://portfolio.kylerassweiler.ca/software/kawasaki-

parser/

Source: https://github.com/rassweiler/kawasaki-as-parser

Robot Project Utility

Mk2

A simple utility written in JS, HTML, CSS, React, and Electron(Node.js). The utility allows the user to view robot backup information from various robot brands(Currently Kawasaki), and is also used to compare two backups then determine any change points. The utility can also be used for work planning.

Site: https://portfolio.kylerassweiler.ca/software/robot-

project-utility/

Source: https://github.com/rassweiler/robot-project-utility

Experience

Engineering Specialist

PLC programming, Robotic Vision (Robeye system), 3D Factory

Design, Robot programming, Project Management

2017 - Present

TEMA (Toyota)

Robotics Technician PLC programming, Robot programming, SCADA programing.

2014 - 2017

FIO Automotive

Operational Technician PLC programming, Robot programming.

2012 - 2014

Abbott Point Of Care

Certificates

Free Code Camp JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures

July 2022 https://www.freecodecamp.org/certification/kylerassweiler/

javascript-algorithms-and-data-structures

Free Code Camp Responsive Web Design

June 2022 https://www.freecodecamp.org/certification/kylerassweiler/

responsive-web-design

Education

Electro-Mechanical Engineering Technician Algonquin College, Ottawa, ON.

2010 - 2012

Computer Animation

Algonquin College, Ottawa, ON.

2007 - 2010